FARAZ KORASANI

Sydney NSW 2067 0451 287 563 Faraz.korasani@gmail.com

Drawing on my 20 years of teaching experience in the ESL, EFL, and coding industries, I am looking forward to making a difference in the classroom.



Also, here's my personal website: https://farazkorasani.github.io/portfolio/

Skills

- Exam Prep (IELTS, iBT, PTE, GRE)
- FAP
- Business English (Business English Result)
- General English
- Academic/Creative Writing
- K-12
- Proofreading
- Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Vue, C#, Git/GitHub)
- Multimedia Design (Processing, p5.js, Adobe Photoshop, FlexClip, Figma)
- Game Development (Unity, Unreal Engine 5)

Qualifications

- CELTA (pass B) International House Sydney, Sydney, Australia
- Bachelor's Degree in English Literature Allameh Tabataba'i University, Tehran, Iran
- Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science Parand University
- Associate Degree in English Literature Allameh Tabataba'i University, Tehran, Iran
- Academic IELTS 8.5
- General IELTS 8.5
- iBT (TOEFL) 118
- GRE 320 (Full Verbal Score)

Publications

• Faraz Korasani. "Q Skills for Success Level 2 Book Review". *English Australia Journal* 37.1 (2021): 103-107.

Professional Experience

Freelance - Sydney, Australia

K-12 English Writing Teacher, Apr. 2024 – Present

- Narrative Writing
- Persuasive Writing
- Text Response
- Creative Response
- Argumentative Analysis
- Expository Writing
- Comparative Analysis
- Reflective Writing

ILSC Sydney – Sydney, Australia

English Teacher, Mar. 2019 – Apr. 2024

- IELTS Preparation Courses (Online and On-Campus)
- English for Academic Purposes Courses (Online and On-Campus)
- General English Courses (Online and On-Campus)

International House Sydney- Sydney, Australia

English Teacher, Jan. 2019 – Feb. 2019

• General English courses; English File 3rd Edition

Tehran Institute of Technology - Tehran, Iran

English and Coding teacher, Aug. 2011 - Aug. 2018

- Exam prep courses; general & academic IELTS, PBT, and iBT
- GRE preparation courses
- General English courses; New Interchange, Passages, and English Result
- Business English courses
- Dogme conversation/free discussion courses
- Accent Reduction Courses
- Creative Coding (Processing)
- Algorithmic Art

Aryanpour Novin Language Institute – Tehran, Iran

English Teacher, Jan 2007 – Jun. 2011

- General English courses; New Interchange, Passages, and American English File
- Dogme conversation/free discussion courses

Freelance – Tehran, Iran

English teacher, Dec. 2005 – Aug. 2018

- Exam prep courses; general & academic IELTS, PBT, and iBT
- General English courses; Streamline, Touchstone & Viewpoint
- Conversation courses; Function & American Street Talk (vol. 1 & 3)

References

- Yulianto Lukito; Cambridge CELTA Senior Trainer at IH and ILSC Australia;
 YLukito@ihsydney.com.au
- Aaron Clark; Head Teacher at ILSC Australia; Aaron.Clark@ilsc.com.au